Sohel Modasiya

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India



sohelmodasiya07@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sohel-modasiya-59795079





Summary

I have over 6 years of experience working in Networking Field. Currently, I am working as a Assistant Manager - Operations in SIFY TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD for STATE BANK OF INDIA Project. Handling team of Gujarat State.

Experienced Associate Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the Networking & information technology and services industry.

Skilled in Networking, Team Leadership, Facility Management, Client Coordination, Service Provider Coordination, Field Calls Management.

ITIL® 4 Specialist Create, Deliver and Support Certified.

Experience



sify Assistant Manager Operations

Sify Technologies Limited.

Sep 2021 - Present (1 month +)

- 1. Working as a Assistant Manager-Operations in SIFY TECHNOLOGIES LTD for STATE BANK OF INDIA-SBI Project.
- 2. Handling Network engineer's team of Gujarat State.
- 3. Working on MPLS Technology, LAN, WAN Monitoring.
- 4. Follow up with Service providers and other stakeholders for provisioning, upgradation, degradation and termination of the link.
- 5. Verification and Escalation for any payment related discrepancy in relation to link database and SLA tools with respective services provider.
- 6. Responsible for management of Devices & Link Uptime.
- 7. Follow-up with link service providers for early restoration of links.

Team Leader

NTT Ltd.

Dec 2017 - Jun 2021 (3 years 7 months)

Team Leader in PUNJAB NATIONAL BANK project. Leading team of Gujarat & Maharashtra state.

- 1. Working on MPLS Technology, LAN, WAN Monitoring.
- 2. Responsible for carrying out regular service improvement plans.
- 3. Follow up with Service providers and other stakeholders for provisioning, upgradation, degradation and termination of the link.
- 4. Responsible to coordinate with NOC to deploy the link and update the link database.
- 5. Decommission of the links.
- 6. Invoice management from BSNL, MTNL and all other TSP's.

- 7. Verification and Escalation for any payment related discrepancy in relation to link database and SLA tools with respective services provider.
- 8. Responsible for management of Devices & Link Uptime.
- 9. Responsible for Managing Escalation and resolving issues on time with coordination of NOC and application owners.
- 10. Building LAN Management.
- 11. Follow-up with field team to reduce link isolated cases.
- 12. Follow-up with link service providers for early restoration of links.

Associate Network Engineer

HCL Technologies

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017 (2 years)

- 1. Network Monitoring for Punjab National Bank.
- 2. Responsible to check all the backup links (ISDN, VSAT, RF)
- 3. Working on Point-to-Point & MPLS Technology.
- 4. Follow up with Service providers for provisioning, upgradation, degradation and termination of the link.
- 5. Field visit in case of any link failure.
- 6. Responsible for management of Devices & Link Uptime.
- 7. Follow-up with link service providers for early restoration of links.

L1 NETWORK SUPPORT ENGINEER

SYNOPHIC SYSTEMS LIMITED

Mar 2015 - Oct 2015 (8 months)

- 1. Working for RELINCE JIO INFOCOM project at Ahmedabad location.
- 2. Installation, Integration, of Cisco Routers such as 901, 920-O, 920-I.
- 3. Provide onsite support for installation and troubleshooting.
- 4, Responsible for L1 activities.
- 5. Visit down sites at specified locations and trouble shoots that sites and get checked by NOC Team.
- 6. Configuration of Microwave and Fiber sites as per the given Network Integrated Protocol.

Wireless Network Engineer

CHANDRA NET PVT LTD

Oct 2014 - Mar 2015 (6 months)

- 1. Responsible to create and design for best coverage area according to the interference level.
- 2. Maintain Wireless Networks Devices.
- 3. Configuration of Network Devices such as UBNT, UBIQUITIOUS devices including Microtek, Nano beam, Nano bridge M5, Rocket M5.
- 4. Works on the IP addressing, MAC binding systems and provide support to field teams.
- 5. Field visit to install any device at site for better network coverage.
- 6. Monitor the links using the root Protocols like SNMP along with Telnet and MRTG in the system.

Education



K.C.T. Engineering College, Gulbarga

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electronics and Communications Engineering 2007 - 2013

M.H.S Himatnagar H.S.C, SCIENCE 2006 - 2007

M.H.S Himatnagar

2004 - 2005

Licenses & Certifications

- ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management AXELOS Global Best Practice
- ITIL® 4 Specialist Create, Deliver and Support Certificate AXELOS Global Best Practice

Skills

Team Management • MPLS Networking • Network Administration • Troubleshooting • Wireless • Project Planning • IP • Recruiting • VoIP • Vendor Management